https://rimtours.com/privacy

Search This Site
Search for:
Skip to content
MenuDay Tours CloseHalf DayCourthouse LoopDead Horse Point SingletrackKlondike BluffMoab Brands Trails SingletrackKlonZo TrailsNavajo RocksBartlett WashNorth Klondike SingletrackMagnificent 7 Trails SingletrackSlickrock TrailAmasa Back / AhabFull DayDead Horse Point SingletrackNavajo RocksNorth Klondike SingletrackMagnificent 7 Trails SingletrackAmasa Back / AhabPorcupine RimSpecialtyDesert SunriseCanyonlands National Park Full DayWhole Enchilada | Hazzard CountyPedal & PaddleInstructional TourWhite Rim in a DayBrowse All Day ToursMake a Day Tour ReservationDay Tour Pricing StructureInquire about AvailabilityMulti-Day Tours CloseMoab AreaWhite Rim 3-DayWhite Rim 4-DayThe Maze 5-DayThe Maze 6-DayKokopelli TrailBest of Moab Mnt. Bike Inn TourNeedles to Moab Canyonlands TourBears Ears Mnt. Bike Weekend 3-DayBears Ears Backcountry Tour 4-DayGrand Staircase-EscalanteVehicle Support ServicesColoradoDurango Intermediate SingletrackDurango – Colorado Trail SingletrackKokopelli TrailKokopelli SingletrackBest of Fruita Mnt. Bike Inn TourBest of Crested Butte Inn TourCrested Butte SingletrackSouthwest UtahBryce to ZionGooseberry Mesa 3-DayGooseberry Mesa 4-DayWest CoastOregon Cascade Mountain SingletrackNorthern ArizonaGrand Canyon North Rim 4-DayGrand Canyon North Rim 5-DayCentral ArizonaBlack Canyon TrailArizona’s Sonoran DesertBrowse All Multi-day ToursMake a Multi-day ReservationMulti-day Tour Pricing StructureInquire about AvailabilityMore CloseRimRim Tours 2020 Mountain Bike SaleAbout Rim ToursOur TeamCustomer ReviewsAdventure West (Rim’s Blog)Trip StuffBike and Gear RentalsWhat to ExpectWhat To BringPhoto Galleries CloseMulti-day Tour Photo GalleriesDay Tour Photo GalleriesDeposit / Cancellation Policies CloseMulti-day Deposit / Cancellation PolicyDay-tour Deposit / Cancellation PolicyVehicle Support Services / Cancellation PolicyPricing Structure CloseMulti-day Tour Pricing StructureDay Tour Pricing StructureFAQs CloseFAQ for Multi-day ToursFAQ for Day ToursTravel InformationWhat To Do In MoabMap of Moab Mtb TrailheadsSubmit a Payment
Day Tour Reservation
Multi-day Tour Reservation
Tour Calendar
This privacy policy sets out how Rim Tours uses and protects any information that you give Rim Tours when you use this website.
Rim Tours is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.
Rim Tours may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from May 25, 2018.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
name
contact information including email address
demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
other information relevant to guest comfort and safety while on our tours
What we do with the information we gather
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
Internal record keeping.
We may use the information to improve our products and services.
We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at info@rimtours.com.
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we are required by law to do so.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please email or call us.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email or call us as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
×
Multi-Day Tour Skill Levels
Our tours range from moderate to intermediate to advanced in difficulty and the trail surfaces may be dirt road, 4wd routes and/or singletrack. Please make sure you are not choosing a tour that is too difficult for your skill level. Call our office if you have questions.
Moderate:
Suitable for riders with an average to good fitness level who engage in some form of regular exercise and are comfortable riding a bike for 2+ hours. Hills and descents are typically of short duration and longer steeper pitches can be easily walked. Trail surfaces will vary and change with occasional obstacles on trail (rocks, roots, sand) that can be either ridden or walked.
We strongly recommend training for your tour by getting on a bike as much as possible to get your butt used to the bike seat!
Intermediate: Suitable for riders with good to excellent fitness level. Previous mountain bike experience is recommended. Trail surfaces may include uneven terrain and narrow trails, singletrack, with occasional obstacles (roots, rocks, sand).
Hills and descents are moderate to strenuous and require some skill.
Riders with minimal mountain bike experience but who have road biking skills or a strong fitness level along with an adventurous spirit may be suitable for an intermediate tour.
Note: Challenging Intermediate Tours require more mountain biking experience due to consistently more challenging terrain.
Advanced: Suitable for experienced mountain bikers only with excellent fitness and strong bike handling skills.
Riding is primarily on rugged 4wd doubletrack with frequent obstacles or high elevation singletrack.
Sections of trail can be very challenging with frequent ascents and descents of significant length.
Most of our advanced level tours are located at elevations ranging from 8,000 to 12,000 feet where trail conditions can change rapidly due to weather conditions and thunderstorms.
Singletrack Tours:
Singletrack trails add an element of technical difficulty because of the narrowness of the trails.
If you are considering an intermediate or advanced singletrack trip, previous experience riding singletrack trails is essential.
Close
×
Day Tour Skill Levels
Our tours range from EASY to MODERATE to INTERMEDIATE to ADVANCED in difficulty. We are happy to discuss what tours are a proper fit for your experience. Please make sure you choose a tour that is appropriate and safe for your ability and fitness level.
Easy:
Tours are suitable for beginner and above riders who are comfortable riding a bike, including children provided they can use hand brakes and are familiar with shifting gears. A moderate fitness level is essential to your enjoyment of this activity. Trail surfaces are typically wider dirt roads which may have occasional obstacles that can be avoided or walked through. Hills will be of short duration and can easily be walked both up or down.
Moderate: Tours are suitable for beginner and above riders with an average to good fitness level that engage in some form of regular exercise. Hills and descents are typically of short duration and longer steeper pitches can be easily walked. Trail surfaces will vary from bumpy dirt roads to 4WD and easy singletrack with occasional obstacles on trail (rocks, roots, sand) that can be either ridden or walked.
Intermediate: Tours are suitable for riders who have previous mountain bike experience and good to excellent fitness. Trail surfaces may include uneven terrain and narrow trails, singletrack, with obstacles (roots, rocks, sand) that range in size from curb to knee high, and occasionally larger. Hills and descents are moderate to strenuous and require some skill. Riders with some mountain bike experience who also have solid road biking skills or a strong fitness level, along with an adventurous spirit, might be suitable for a lower level intermediate tour.
Advanced: Tours are suitable for more seasoned mountain bikers with excellent fitness and very strong bike handling skills. Riding is primarily on rough doubletrack and singletrack with frequent obstacles that are typically larger than knee high. Sections of trail can be very challenging with frequent ascents and descents.
Singletrack Tours: Singletrack trails add an element of technical difficulty because of the narrowness of the trails. If you are considering an intermediate or advanced singletrack tour, previous experience riding singletrack trails is essential.
Close
Translate »
Updated June 25, 2020:
To All Rim Tours’ guests and potential guests:
Moab and most of Utah have relaxed restrictions in phases since the shutdown of Moab and most of the state. Likewise, the areas we travel to for our summer multi-day tours have also imposed fewer restrictions than before so our operations are back up and running in all areas. With our re-opening we have new protocols in place to keep both you and our staff as safe as possible and we are working with our guests individually to make sure your expectations and ours are met. Part of this is having each guest review and sign a Participation Contract (for Day Tours and for Multi-day Tours) in addition to a waiver for your tour. We also have a Covid Mitigation Procedures document to explain our Multi-Day Tour protocols.
We are running our Day Tours throughout the summer in Moab, leaving town early to beat the heat and our Multi-Day Tours are gradually ramping up after so many of you had to cancel. We are working with families and groups to create private experiences and pairing smaller groups together to meet our minimums for running a trip.
We truly appreciate our dedicated guests and staff for sticking with us and helping us survive the loss of over half of our season. Thank you!
Be safe, be well and ride your bike!
Kirstin, Matt and the Rim Tours Staff
×
Grand Staircase-Escalante Elevation Profile
×
Porcupine (Kokopelli, UPS, LPS, Porcupine Rim) Elevation Profile
Amasa Back Half-day Elevation Profile (Hymasa/Ahab)
